<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Ehmi</title>
    <link href="https://blog.ehmad.site/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://blog.ehmad.site" />
    <updated>2025-03-03T10:20:27+05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Ehmad</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://blog.ehmad.site</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Self-Hosting Bitwarden with Docker Compose on Alpine linux</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ehmad</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.ehmad.site/self-hosting-bitwarden-with-docker-compose-on-alpine-linux/"/>
        <id>https://blog.ehmad.site/self-hosting-bitwarden-with-docker-compose-on-alpine-linux/</id>

        <updated>2025-03-03T10:20:27+05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Bitwarden is a popular open-source password manager that allows users to self-host their own instance for enhanced privacy and control. Using Docker Compose, you can deploy Bitwarden with a custom network and static IP addresses, making it ideal for homelab enthusiasts or small organizations. This&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Bitwarden is a popular open-source password manager that allows users to self-host their own instance for enhanced privacy and control. Using Docker Compose, you can deploy Bitwarden with a custom network and static IP addresses, making it ideal for homelab enthusiasts or small organizations. This guide walks through setting up the Bitwarden unified beta deployment (<code>bitwarden/self-host:beta</code>) with a MariaDB database, connected to an existing Docker network, and troubleshoot common issues along the way.</p><h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites</h2>
<ul>
<li>Docker and Docker Compose installed on your system.</li>
<li>A custom Docker network (e.g., <code>homelab_private_network</code>) already created.</li>
<li>Basic familiarity with Docker commands and YAML configuration.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="step-1-define-the-docker-compose-file">Step 1: Define the Docker Compose File</h2>
<p>The Bitwarden unified deployment simplifies self-hosting by bundling most components into a single container, though it still requires a separate database. We’ll use MariaDB for this setup. Below is a <code>docker-compose.yml</code> file configured to join an existing network with static IPs.</p><h3 id="docker-composeyml"><code>docker-compose.yml</code></h3>
<pre><code class="language-yaml">services:
  bitwarden:
    depends_on:
      - db
    env_file:
      - settings.env
    image: bitwarden/self-host:beta
    restart: always
    ports:
      - &quot;80:8080&quot;
      - &quot;443:8443&quot;
    volumes:
      - ./bitwarden-data:/etc/bitwarden
      - ./logs:/var/log/bitwarden
    networks:
      homelab_private_network:
        ipv4_address: 192.168.2.110

  db:
    environment:
      MARIADB_USER: &quot;bitwarden&quot;
      MARIADB_PASSWORD: &quot;[REDACTED]&quot;
      MARIADB_DATABASE: &quot;bitwarden_vault&quot;
      MARIADB_RANDOM_ROOT_PASSWORD: &quot;true&quot;
    image: mariadb:10
    restart: always
    volumes:
      - ./db-data:/var/lib/mysql
    networks:
      homelab_private_network:
        ipv4_address: 192.168.2.111

networks:
  homelab_private_network:
    external: true
</code></pre>
<h3 id="key-components">Key Components</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Bitwarden Service</strong>: Uses the <code>bitwarden/self-host:beta</code> image, maps ports <code>80</code> and <code>443</code> to internal ports <code>8080</code> and <code>8443</code>, and mounts volumes for configuration and logs.</li>
<li><strong>MariaDB Service</strong>: Runs a MySQL-compatible database with predefined credentials and a random root password for security.</li>
<li><strong>Network</strong>: Joins an existing <code>homelab_private_network</code> with static IPs (<code>192.168.2.110</code> for Bitwarden, <code>192.168.2.111</code> for MariaDB).</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Note</strong>: The <code>version</code> field (e.g., <code>3.7</code>) is omitted as it’s obsolete in Docker Compose v2. The schema is inferred from the features used.</p></blockquote>
<h2 id="step-2-configure-environment-variables">Step 2: Configure Environment Variables</h2>
<p>Bitwarden requires environment variables for database connectivity and domain settings. Create a <code>settings.env</code> file in the same directory as <code>docker-compose.yml</code>.</p><h3 id="settingsenv"><code>settings.env</code></h3>
<pre><code>DOMAIN=http://192.168.2.110
DATABASE_PROVIDER=mysql
DATABASE_SERVER=db
DATABASE_NAME=bitwarden_vault
DATABASE_USERNAME=bitwarden
DATABASE_PASSWORD=[REDACTED]
ADMIN_ENABLED=true
SMTP_HOST=smtp.example.com
SMTP_PORT=587
SMTP_SSL=false
SMTP_USERNAME=[REDACTED]
SMTP_PASSWORD=[REDACTED]
</code></pre>
<h3 id="explanation">Explanation</h3>
<ul>
<li><code>DOMAIN</code>: Set to the Bitwarden container’s static IP (adjust for your setup or use a domain with SSL).</li>
<li><code>DATABASE_*</code>: Matches the MariaDB service’s credentials and service name.</li>
<li><code>ADMIN_ENABLED</code>: Enables the admin interface (optional).</li>
<li><code>SMTP_*</code>: Configures email notifications (optional; replace with your SMTP provider’s details).</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Security Tip</strong>: Replace <code>[REDACTED]</code> placeholders with strong, unique passwords and credentials.</p></blockquote>
<h2 id="step-3-prepare-the-environment">Step 3: Prepare the Environment</h2>
<p>Create directories for persistent data:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">mkdir -p ./bitwarden-data ./logs ./db-data
</code></pre>
<p>Ensure your custom network exists and its subnet includes the chosen IPs. Check with:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">docker network inspect homelab_private_network
</code></pre>
<p>Example output might show a subnet of <code>192.168.2.0/24</code>, supporting IPs from <code>192.168.2.1</code> to <code>192.168.2.254</code>. Adjust the IPs in <code>docker-compose.yml</code> if they don’t match (e.g., if the subnet were <code>192.168.0.0/24</code>, use <code>192.168.0.110</code> and <code>192.168.0.111</code>).</p><h2 id="step-4-deploy-the-services">Step 4: Deploy the Services</h2>
<p>Start the containers in detached mode:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">docker compose up -d
</code></pre>
<p>Verify they’re running:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">docker compose ps
</code></pre>
<p>You should see both <code>bitwarden</code> and <code>db</code> listed as <code>Up</code>.</p><h2 id="step-5-troubleshooting-common-issues">Step 5: Troubleshooting Common Issues</h2>
<h3 id="issue-1-obsolete-version-warning">Issue 1: Obsolete <code>version</code> Warning</h3>
<p>If you see a warning like:</p><pre><code>WARN[0000] docker-compose.yaml: the attribute `version` is obsolete...
</code></pre>
<p>Remove the <code>version</code> line from <code>docker-compose.yml</code>. It’s no longer needed in modern Docker Compose versions.</p><h3 id="issue-2-subnet-mismatch-error">Issue 2: Subnet Mismatch Error</h3>
<p>An error like:</p><pre><code>Error response from daemon: invalid config for network homelab_private_network: ... no configured subnet or ip-range contain the IP address 192.168.0.111
</code></pre>
<p>means the assigned IPs don’t match the network’s subnet. Inspect the network:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">docker network inspect homelab_private_network
</code></pre>
<p>If the subnet is <code>192.168.2.0/24</code> but your IPs are <code>192.168.0.x</code>, update <code>docker-compose.yml</code> to use <code>192.168.2.110</code> and <code>192.168.2.111</code>, then restart:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">docker compose down
docker compose up -d
</code></pre>
<h3 id="issue-3-container-exits-immediately">Issue 3: Container Exits Immediately</h3>
<p>If <code>bitwarden</code> or <code>db</code> stops (check with <code>docker compose ps -a</code>), view logs:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">docker compose logs bitwarden
docker compose logs db
</code></pre>
<p>Common causes include mismatched database credentials or missing SMTP settings (though SMTP is optional).</p><h2 id="step-6-access-bitwarden">Step 6: Access Bitwarden</h2>
<p>Once running, access Bitwarden at <code>http://192.168.2.110</code> (or your chosen IP) in a browser. Set up an account and test functionality. For production, consider:</p><ul>
<li>Adding SSL with a reverse proxy (e.g., Nginx or Traefik) <strong>Important</strong>.</li>
<li>Backing up the <code>./bitwarden-data</code> and <code>./db-data</code> directories.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Self-hosting Bitwarden with Docker Compose on a custom network offers flexibility and control over your password management on alpine linux. By assigning static IPs and troubleshooting subnet issues, you can integrate it seamlessly into an existing homelab setup. The unified beta deployment simplifies the process, making it accessible even for those new to Docker and alpine.</p><p>For advanced configurations, explore Bitwarden’s official <a href="https://bitwarden.com/help/install-on-premise-linux/">documentation</a> or integrate cloud features with an installation ID and key. Happy self-hosting!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Tenda AC9 Firmware Analysis</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ehmad</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.ehmad.site/tenda-ac9-firmware-analysis/"/>
        <id>https://blog.ehmad.site/tenda-ac9-firmware-analysis/</id>

        <updated>2025-02-23T15:59:55+05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Reverse Engineering the Tenda AC9 Firmware Routers are the unsung heroes of our connected lives—quietly humming away, keeping us online. But what’s really going on inside them? I recently got curious about my Tenda AC9 router and decided to crack open its firmware—US_AC9V1.0BR_V15.03.05.15_multi_TDE01.bin—to see what&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h1 id="reverse-engineering-the-tenda-ac9-firmware">Reverse Engineering the Tenda AC9 Firmware</h1>
<p>Routers are the unsung heroes of our connected lives—quietly humming away, keeping us online. But what’s <em>really</em> going on inside them? I recently got curious about my Tenda AC9 router and decided to crack open its firmware—<code>US_AC9V1.0BR_V15.03.05.15_multi_TDE01.bin</code>—to see what secrets it holds. Spoiler: it’s a mix of the expected, the quirky, and the slightly unsettling. Here’s what I found, how I got there, and why it might matter.</p><h2 id="step-1-cracking-the-shell-with-binwalk">Step 1: Cracking the Shell with Binwalk</h2>
<p>First things first—I needed to unpack the firmware. It’s a 7.4MB file, a u-boot uImage for a Linux/ARM kernel, timestamped October 29, 2020. Sounded like a job for <code>binwalk</code>, a go-to tool for firmware analysis. After installing it (<code>sudo apt install binwalk</code>), I ran a quick scan:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">wget https://github.com/mrxehmad/Tenda-AC9-Firmware-Analysis/raw/refs/heads/main/US_AC9V1.0BR_V15.03.05.15_multi_TDE01.zip
</code></pre>
<pre><code class="language-bash">binwalk US_AC9V1.0BR_V15.03.05.15_multi_TDE01.bin
</code></pre>
<p>The output revealed a TRX header, an LZMA-compressed kernel, and a SquashFS filesystem. To get inside, I extracted it:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">binwalk -e US_AC9V1.0BR_V15.03.05.15_multi_TDE01.bin
</code></pre>
<p>This gave me a folder with a compressed kernel (<code>5C.LZMA</code>) and a filesystem (<code>18EB48.squashfs</code>). One more command to decompress the filesystem:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">unsquashfs -f -d squashfs-root 18EB48.squashfs
</code></pre>
<p>And voilà—a treasure trove of files in <code>squashfs-root/</code>. Time to explore.</p><h2 id="step-2-open-ports-and-a-network-surprise">Step 2: Open Ports and a Network Surprise</h2>
<p>Before diving into the files, I scanned my router (<code>10.1.15.1</code>) with Nmap to see what it’s exposing:</p><pre><code>PORT      STATE SERVICE
80/tcp    open  http
5500/tcp  open  hotline
8180/tcp  open  unknown
9000/tcp  open  cslistener
10004/tcp open  emcrmirccd
</code></pre>
<p>Port 80? Expected for the web interface. 8180? Probably a secondary UI (more on that later). But 5500, 9000, and 10004? Those raised eyebrows. “Hotline” and “emcrmirccd” didn’t scream “router,” so I knew I had some digging to do.</p><h2 id="step-3-the-filesystem-tells-a-story">Step 3: The Filesystem Tells a Story</h2>
<p>Inside <code>squashfs-root/</code>, I found a mix of binaries, libraries, and configs. Nginx was running on port 8180 (<code>/usr/bin/nginx</code>), serving a Luci interface with a FastCGI backend on 8188 (<code>/usr/bin/app_data_center</code>). Port 80 was handled by <code>httpd</code>—standard stuff. But then things got interesting.</p><h3 id="hardcoded-connections">Hardcoded Connections</h3>
<p>Grepping through the files, I spotted hardcoded IPs and domains:</p><ul>
<li><code>cloud.tenda.com.cn</code></li>
<li><code>182.254.148.51</code></li>
<li><code>download.cloud.tenda.com.cn</code></li>
<li><code>182.254.218.214</code></li>
<li><code>182.254.136.200</code></li>
</ul>
<p>These popped up in files like <code>./bin/auto_discover</code>, which sends your MAC address and timestamp to <code>api.cloud.tenda.com.cn/route/mac/v1</code>. Device tracking, perhaps? Meanwhile, <code>httpd</code> fetches ad URLs from <code>api.cloud.tenda.com.cn/route/adverts/v1</code>, defaulting to <code>www.tenda.com.cn</code> if it fails. An old-school User-Agent (<code>MSIE 5.01</code>) hinted this code hasn’t been touched in years.</p><h3 id="quirky-binaries">Quirky Binaries</h3>
<ul>
<li><code>./bin/speedtest</code>: Pings domains like <code>www.taobao.com</code> and <code>www.google.com</code>—likely a bandwidth test.</li>
<li><code>./bin/88ip</code>: Sends XML to <code>link.dipserver.com</code> for dynamic DNS.</li>
<li><code>./bin/logserver</code>: Tries (and often fails) to ship logs somewhere external.</li>
<li><code>./usr/sbin/telnetd</code>: A Telnet server! No startup script activated it, but its presence felt like a debug leftover.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="firewall-rules">Firewall Rules</h3>
<p>Hardcoded <code>iptables</code> commands caught my eye:</p><pre><code>iptables -A OUTPUT -p udp --dport %d -m state --state NEW -j %s
iptables -A %s -o %s -j DROP
</code></pre>
<p>These seem to manage outbound traffic—maybe to those Tenda cloud servers?</p><h2 id="step-4-what-does-it-mean">Step 4: What Does It Mean?</h2>
<p>This firmware is chatty. It phones home to Tenda’s cloud, potentially sharing device info, fetching ads, and running services on non-standard ports (5500 and 10004 still elude me—debug backdoors?). The Telnet binary is dormant but tempting for anyone with root access. And those hardcoded IPs? A security researcher’s red flag—perfect for spoofing or tracking.</p><h2 id="why-it-matters">Why It Matters</h2>
<p>Routers like the Tenda AC9 are everywhere, yet we rarely peek inside. This little adventure showed me how much they’re doing behind the scenes—some useful, some questionable. I’ve dumped my findings on GitHub (link below) with extraction steps, hoping others might join the fun. Could 5500 be a mislabeled Telnet port? Is <code>libupnp.so</code> behind 9000? I’m a newbie at this, but tools like Ghidra are calling—I’ll dive deeper if you do.</p><p>What do you think? Ever analyzed your own gear? Let’s swap notes!</p><ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/mrxehmad/Tenda-AC9-Firmware-Analysis">Tenda AC9 Firmware Analysis</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/mrxehmad/api.cloud.tenda.com.cn">api.cloud.tenda.com.cn</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SC0p30N3/Tenda-AC15-Firmware-V15.03.05.18">Tenda AC15 Analysis</a> </li>
<li><a href="https://ea.github.io/blog/2013/10/18/tenda-backdoor/">Tenda Backdoor Blog</a></li>
</ul>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>User Reports Privacy Indicator Issue with Google Assistant on Pixel Phones</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ehmad</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.ehmad.site/user-reports-privacy-indicator-issue-with-google-assistant-on-pixel-phones/"/>
        <id>https://blog.ehmad.site/user-reports-privacy-indicator-issue-with-google-assistant-on-pixel-phones/</id>

        <updated>2025-02-14T18:35:30+05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    A Pixel phone user recently reported a potentially concerning behavior related to Google Assistant and the microphone privacy indicator. According to the user, when activating Google Assistant using the voice command “Hey Google,” the microphone privacy indicator did not appear immediately. However, once the conversation&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>A Pixel phone user recently reported a potentially concerning behavior related to Google Assistant and the microphone privacy indicator. According to the user, when activating Google Assistant using the voice command “Hey Google,” the microphone privacy indicator did not appear immediately. However, once the conversation with Google Assistant began, the indicator appeared, signaling that the microphone was in use. This raised questions about whether Google Assistant was listening before displaying the indicator.</p><h3 id="possible-explanations-for-this-behavior">Possible Explanations for This Behavior</h3>
<ol>
<li><p><strong>Wake-Up Happens at a Lower System Level</strong><br>Google Assistant continuously listens for the wake phrase “Hey Google” using on-device speech recognition. This process does not trigger the microphone indicator because it operates at a system level without actively recording or sending data. The indicator only appears once Google Assistant starts processing the user’s request.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Delayed Privacy Indicator</strong><br>There might be a slight delay in the system UI updating to show the microphone indicator, especially if the phone is under load. This could explain why the indicator appears after Google Assistant starts responding rather than immediately upon activation.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Different Microphone Access Levels</strong><br>System-level apps like Google Assistant might bypass standard privacy indicator rules when passively listening for the wake word. The microphone is formally marked “in use” only when the Assistant starts processing a request.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Possible Software Bug</strong><br>If this behavior is new or inconsistent, it could be a software glitch introduced in a recent Android update. Google has previously adjusted privacy indicators, and any unexpected changes should be monitored for potential fixes in future updates.</p></li>
</ol>
<h3 id="how-users-can-investigate-further">How Users Can Investigate Further</h3>
<p>If you’re experiencing this issue and want to ensure your privacy, here are a few steps to take:</p><ul>
<li><p><strong>Check Mic Usage in Privacy Dashboard</strong><br>Navigate to <strong>Settings &gt; Privacy &gt; Permission Manager &gt; Microphone</strong> to see which apps have accessed the microphone and when.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Disable “Hey Google” for Testing</strong><br>Try turning off the voice activation feature (<strong>Settings &gt; Google &gt; Assistant &gt; Hey Google &amp; Voice Match</strong>) and manually activating the Assistant with the power button or gesture. If the indicator appears immediately with manual activation, it suggests a difference in how Google Assistant handles wake-word detection.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Use a Third-Party Mic Monitoring App</strong><br>Apps like <strong>Access Dots</strong> or <strong>Bouncer</strong> can provide additional insights into microphone access and alert users to unexpected mic activity.</p></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="should-users-be-concerned">Should Users Be Concerned?</h3>
<p>While this behavior does not necessarily indicate unauthorized microphone access, it does highlight a gap in transparency regarding when the microphone is actively listening. Google states that Assistant only listens for the wake word and does not store audio until activated. However, privacy-conscious users may want to take extra precautions to verify this claim.</p><p>If you’ve noticed similar behavior on your Pixel or another Android device, sharing your experience can help determine whether this is an isolated issue or a broader software concern.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to Use Discord Webhooks </title>
        <author>
            <name>Ehmad</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.ehmad.site/how-to-use-discord-webhooks/"/>
        <id>https://blog.ehmad.site/how-to-use-discord-webhooks/</id>

        <updated>2025-02-03T13:32:35+05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Discord webhooks are a powerful tool for integrating external services with your Discord server. They allow you to automate messages, send notifications, and even create custom bots without needing to write complex code. In this article, we’ll explore what Discord webhooks are, how to set&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Discord webhooks are a powerful tool for integrating external services with your Discord server. They allow you to automate messages, send notifications, and even create custom bots without needing to write complex code. In this article, we’ll explore what Discord webhooks are, how to set them up, and various ways you can use them to enhance your server.</p><hr>
<h2 id="what-are-discord-webhooks"><strong>What Are Discord Webhooks?</strong></h2>
<p>A webhook is essentially a way for an external application or service to send automated messages to a specific channel in your Discord server. Instead of manually posting updates, webhooks enable real-time communication between your server and other platforms like GitHub, Jenkins, monitoring tools, or even custom scripts.</p><p>Webhooks are lightweight, easy to set up, and don’t require you to build a full-fledged bot. They’re perfect for sending notifications, logging events, or automating repetitive tasks.</p><hr>
<h2 id="how-to-create-a-discord-webhook"><strong>How to Create a Discord Webhook</strong></h2>
<p>Before you can start using webhooks, you need to create one in your Discord server. Here’s how:</p><h3 id="step-1-navigate-to-channel-settings"><strong>Step 1: Navigate to Channel Settings</strong></h3>
<ol>
<li>Open your Discord server.</li>
<li>Go to the channel where you want the webhook to post messages.</li>
<li>Click on the gear icon (⚙️) next to the channel name to open the channel settings.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="step-2-create-a-webhook"><strong>Step 2: Create a Webhook</strong></h3>
<ol>
<li>In the channel settings, go to <strong>Integrations</strong> &gt; <strong>Webhooks</strong>.</li>
<li>Click <strong>Create Webhook</strong>.</li>
<li>Give your webhook a name (e.g., “Notification Bot”).</li>
<li>Select the channel where the webhook will post messages.</li>
<li>Optionally, upload an avatar image to customize the webhook’s appearance.</li>
<li>Click <strong>Copy Webhook URL</strong> and save it securely. This URL is essential for sending messages via the webhook.</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<h2 id="how-to-send-messages-using-a-webhook"><strong>How to Send Messages Using a Webhook</strong></h2>
<p>Once you’ve created a webhook, you can start sending messages to your Discord server. Below are examples of how to do this using different methods.</p><h3 id="1-using-curl-command"><strong>1. Using <code>curl</code> Command</strong></h3>
<p>You can send a simple message to your Discord channel using the <code>curl</code> command in your terminal:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">curl -X POST -H &quot;Content-Type: application/json&quot; \
-d &#39;{&quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hello, this is a test message from my webhook!&quot;}&#39; \
https://discord.com/api/webhooks/YOUR_WEBHOOK_URL_HERE
</code></pre>
<p>Replace <code>YOUR_WEBHOOK_URL_HERE</code> with the actual webhook URL you copied earlier.</p><h3 id="2-using-python"><strong>2. Using Python</strong></h3>
<p>If you prefer scripting, here’s how to send a message using Python:</p><pre><code class="language-python">import requests

webhook_url = &quot;https://discord.com/api/webhooks/YOUR_WEBHOOK_URL_HERE&quot;
data = {&quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hello, this is a test message from my webhook!&quot;}

response = requests.post(webhook_url, json=data)

if response.status_code == 204:
    print(&quot;Message sent successfully!&quot;)
else:
    print(f&quot;Failed to send message: {response.status_code}, {response.text}&quot;)
</code></pre>
<h3 id="3-using-postman-or-insomnia"><strong>3. Using Postman or Insomnia</strong></h3>
<p>For non-programmers, tools like <a href="https://www.postman.com/">Postman</a> or <a href="https://insomnia.rest/">Insomnia</a> can be used to manually send HTTP POST requests to the webhook URL.</p><hr>
<h2 id="customizing-webhook-messages"><strong>Customizing Webhook Messages</strong></h2>
<p>Discord webhooks allow you to customize the sender’s name, avatar, and even send rich embeds for more visually appealing messages.</p><h3 id="1-custom-sender-name-and-avatar"><strong>1. Custom Sender Name and Avatar</strong></h3>
<p>You can override the default webhook name and avatar by including the <code>username</code> and <code>avatar_url</code> fields in your payload:</p><pre><code class="language-json">{
  &quot;username&quot;: &quot;My Custom Bot&quot;,
  &quot;avatar_url&quot;: &quot;https://example.com/avatar.png&quot;,
  &quot;content&quot;: &quot;This message is sent by a custom bot!&quot;
}
</code></pre>
<h3 id="2-sending-rich-embeds"><strong>2. Sending Rich Embeds</strong></h3>
<p>Embeds allow you to send structured and visually appealing messages. Here’s an example of an embed payload:</p><pre><code class="language-json">{
  &quot;embeds&quot;: [
    {
      &quot;title&quot;: &quot;New Blog Post!&quot;,
      &quot;description&quot;: &quot;Check out our latest article on how to use webhooks.&quot;,
      &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://example.com/blog-post&quot;,
      &quot;color&quot;: 16711680,
      &quot;fields&quot;: [
        {
          &quot;name&quot;: &quot;Author&quot;,
          &quot;value&quot;: &quot;John Doe&quot;,
          &quot;inline&quot;: true
        },
        {
          &quot;name&quot;: &quot;Published Date&quot;,
          &quot;value&quot;: &quot;2023-10-01&quot;,
          &quot;inline&quot;: true
        }
      ],
      &quot;thumbnail&quot;: {
        &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://example.com/thumbnail.jpg&quot;
      }
    }
  ]
}
</code></pre>
<p>Send this payload using <code>curl</code>, Python, or any other method.</p><hr>
<h2 id="use-cases-for-discord-webhooks"><strong>Use Cases for Discord Webhooks</strong></h2>
<p>Here are some practical ways you can use webhooks to enhance your Discord server:</p><h3 id="1-notifications-from-external-services"><strong>1. Notifications from External Services</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>GitHub</strong>: Get notifications for new commits, issues, or pull requests.</li>
<li><strong>Jenkins</strong>: Notify your team when a build succeeds or fails.</li>
<li><strong>Uptime Monitoring</strong>: Alert your team if a server goes down.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="2-logging-system"><strong>2. Logging System</strong></h3>
<p>Use webhooks to log events from your applications or servers. For example:</p><ul>
<li>Log errors or warnings directly to a dedicated “logs” channel.</li>
<li>Monitor server health and send alerts when something goes wrong.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="3-moderation-alerts"><strong>3. Moderation Alerts</strong></h3>
<p>Set up a script or bot that monitors your server for certain activities (e.g., spam detection, keyword filtering) and sends moderation alerts via the webhook.</p><h3 id="4-game-or-event-notifications"><strong>4. Game or Event Notifications</strong></h3>
<p>If you’re running a gaming community, use webhooks to notify users about:</p><ul>
<li>Upcoming game releases.</li>
<li>Server maintenance schedules.</li>
<li>Tournament announcements.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="5-automated-announcements"><strong>5. Automated Announcements</strong></h3>
<p>Use webhooks to automate recurring announcements, such as:</p><ul>
<li>Daily reminders.</li>
<li>Weekly updates.</li>
<li>Event countdowns.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="security-tips-for-using-webhooks"><strong>Security Tips for Using Webhooks</strong></h2>
<p>While webhooks are convenient, they can also pose security risks if not handled properly. Here are some tips to keep your webhooks secure:</p><ol>
<li><strong>Keep Your Webhook URL Secret</strong>: Treat your webhook URL like a password. Anyone with access to it can send messages to your server.</li>
<li><strong>Delete Unused Webhooks</strong>: If you no longer need a webhook, delete it to prevent misuse.</li>
<li><strong>Regenerate Webhooks if Compromised</strong>: If you suspect your webhook has been compromised, delete it and create a new one.</li>
<li><strong>Limit Permissions</strong>: Ensure the webhook only posts to the intended channel and doesn’t have unnecessary permissions.</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<h2 id="troubleshooting-common-issues"><strong>Troubleshooting Common Issues</strong></h2>
<h3 id="1-unknown-webhook-error"><strong>1. “Unknown Webhook” Error</strong></h3>
<p>This error occurs if the webhook URL is invalid, deleted, or disabled. Double-check the URL and ensure the webhook still exists in your server settings.</p><h3 id="2-rate-limits"><strong>2. Rate Limits</strong></h3>
<p>Discord imposes rate limits on webhooks. If you’re sending too many requests in a short period, you may be temporarily blocked. Wait a few minutes before trying again.</p><h3 id="3-formatting-issues"><strong>3. Formatting Issues</strong></h3>
<p>Ensure your JSON payload is correctly formatted. Missing brackets, quotes, or commas can cause errors.</p><hr>
<h2 id="conclusion"><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>
<p>Discord webhooks are a versatile and easy-to-use tool for automating messages and integrating external services with your server. Whether you’re sending notifications, logging events, or creating custom bots, webhooks can help streamline your workflows and keep your community informed.</p><p>By following the steps outlined in this guide, you can set up and use webhooks effectively while keeping your server secure. Experiment with different use cases and customize your messages to make the most of this powerful feature!</p><p>Happy automating! 🚀</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Phishing Attack Chain Report - Fiverr</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ehmad</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.ehmad.site/phishing-attack-chain-report-fiverr/"/>
        <id>https://blog.ehmad.site/phishing-attack-chain-report-fiverr/</id>

        <updated>2025-01-26T21:23:13+05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Phishing Attack Chain Report Incident Overview: I recently encountered a phishing attempt within my Fiverr inbox. The attacker used a GIF image to bypass Fiverr’s security measures and avoid detection. The GIF contained a QR code that, when scanned, directed me to a phishing page.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>Phishing Attack Chain Report</strong></p><p><strong>Incident Overview:</strong>
I recently encountered a phishing attempt within my Fiverr inbox. The attacker used a GIF image to bypass Fiverr’s security measures and avoid detection. The GIF contained a QR code that, when scanned, directed me to a phishing page.</p><p><strong>Phishing URL:</strong><br>Initial URL: <a href="https://fiverr.offer984732.cfd/7ky7njr1pzz7970t">https://fiverr.offer984732.cfd/7ky7njr1pzz7970t</a></p><p><strong>Attack Chain:</strong></p><ol>
<li><p><strong>Initial Contact:</strong>  </p><ul>
<li>The phishing attempt began with a message in my Fiverr inbox containing a GIF image.</li>
<li>The GIF displayed a QR code instead of a direct link, likely to circumvent Fiverr’s security mechanisms.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Phishing Page:</strong>  </p><ul>
<li>Scanning the QR code redirected me to a phishing website disguised to resemble Fiverr’s official payment page.</li>
<li>The page prompted me to “receive payment” from a client by adding my credit card details.</li>
<li>Notably, right-clicking and other browser functions, such as saving the page, were disabled to prevent analysis or inspection.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Redirection to Payment Form:</strong>  </p><ul>
<li>Upon attempting to “receive funds,” I was redirected to another URL:
<a href="https://fiverr.offer984732.cfd/merchant/order/7ky7njr1pzz7970t">https://fiverr.offer984732.cfd/merchant/order/7ky7njr1pzz7970t</a></li>
<li>This page requested full credit card details under the guise of processing the payment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Transaction Failure:</strong>  </p><ul>
<li>After entering test card details, the page displayed a “transaction failed” message.</li>
<li>This indicates the phishing attempt’s goal was purely to collect financial information rather than process any real transaction.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Observations and Indicators of Compromise (IoCs):</strong></p><ul>
<li>The URL contains suspicious subdomains and random alphanumeric paths.</li>
<li>The use of QR codes in phishing attempts to avoid link detection.</li>
<li>Browser functions such as right-clicking being disabled, which is a common phishing tactic.</li>
<li>Fake payment processing followed by a transaction failure message.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Recommendations:</strong></p><ol>
<li><strong>Avoid Scanning Unknown QR Codes:</strong>  <ul>
<li>Do not scan QR codes from unknown or unverified sources, especially in online freelance platforms.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Verify URLs Carefully:</strong>  <ul>
<li>Always cross-check URLs and avoid interacting with unfamiliar domains.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Enable Security Features:</strong>  <ul>
<li>Use browser extensions and security tools to identify phishing sites.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Report the Incident:</strong>  <ul>
<li>Report such incidents to Fiverr’s support team and relevant cybersecurity authorities.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Monitor Financial Accounts:</strong>  <ul>
<li>If any sensitive information was entered, monitor bank statements and enable fraud alerts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong>
This phishing attempt leveraged an innovative technique by embedding a QR code in a GIF to bypass detection and used social engineering to prompt credit card submission. Users should remain vigilant and report suspicious activity to prevent potential financial loss.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Data Communications and Networking 5th edition</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ehmad</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.ehmad.site/data-communications-and-networking-5th-edition/"/>
        <id>https://blog.ehmad.site/data-communications-and-networking-5th-edition/</id>
            <category term="book summery"/>

        <updated>2025-01-08T19:14:02+05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Chapter 18: Introduction to Network Layer in Data Communications and Networking (5th edition) by Behrouz A. Forouzan: The network layer plays a critical role in delivering data between devices over interconnected networks. It provides the following key services: Packet switching is a fundamental method for&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>Chapter 18: Introduction to Network Layer</strong> in Data Communications and Networking (5th edition) by Behrouz A. Forouzan:</p><hr>
<h3 id="181-network-layer-services"><strong>18.1 NETWORK-LAYER SERVICES</strong></h3>
<p>The network layer plays a critical role in delivering data between devices over interconnected networks. It provides the following key services:</p><h4 id="1811-packetizing"><strong>18.1.1 Packetizing</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Definition</strong>: Packetizing is the process of dividing large chunks of data into smaller units called packets, which are easier to manage, transmit, and process.</li>
<li><strong>Structure</strong>: Each packet contains:<ul>
<li><strong>Payload</strong>: The actual data being transmitted.</li>
<li><strong>Header</strong>: Contains metadata such as the source and destination addresses, sequence numbers, and error-checking information.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Purpose</strong>: <ul>
<li>Facilitates efficient use of the network.</li>
<li>Allows for error detection and recovery by retransmitting only the affected packets instead of the entire data.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="1812-routing-and-forwarding"><strong>18.1.2 Routing and Forwarding</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Routing</strong>:<ul>
<li>Involves determining the optimal path for packets to travel from the source to the destination.</li>
<li>Algorithms like Dijkstra’s and Bellman-Ford are commonly used.</li>
<li>Factors considered: network topology, link costs, and policy constraints.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Forwarding</strong>:<ul>
<li>The act of moving a packet to its next destination (next-hop router or the final recipient).</li>
<li>Based on information in the routing table, the router decides the best outgoing link.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="1813-other-services"><strong>18.1.3 Other Services</strong></h4>
<ol>
<li><strong>Error Handling</strong>:<ul>
<li>Detects and sometimes corrects errors in transmitted packets.</li>
<li>Error detection methods like checksums are used.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Quality of Service (QoS)</strong>:<ul>
<li>Ensures performance requirements such as bandwidth, delay, and jitter are met.</li>
<li>Differentiates traffic types (e.g., voice, video, or text) to prioritize critical data.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<h3 id="182-packet-switching"><strong>18.2 PACKET SWITCHING</strong></h3>
<p>Packet switching is a fundamental method for data transfer in modern networks, enabling flexibility and efficiency. It involves breaking data into smaller packets that are sent independently.</p><h4 id="1821-datagram-approach-connectionless-service"><strong>18.2.1 Datagram Approach: Connectionless Service</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Characteristics</strong>:<ul>
<li>Each packet is treated as an independent entity.</li>
<li>Packets may take different paths through the network to reach the destination.</li>
<li>Each packet includes full routing information (source and destination addresses).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Advantages</strong>:<ul>
<li>Highly scalable and robust.</li>
<li>No need for establishing or maintaining a connection.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Example</strong>: The Internet Protocol (IP) operates using this approach.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="1822-virtual-circuit-approach-connection-oriented-service"><strong>18.2.2 Virtual-Circuit Approach: Connection-Oriented Service</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Characteristics</strong>:<ul>
<li>A logical connection is established between the source and destination before data transfer.</li>
<li>All packets follow the same pre-established path, ensuring order.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Advantages</strong>:<ul>
<li>Reliable communication with guaranteed sequencing and error detection.</li>
<li>Simplified processing at intermediate routers.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Example</strong>: Asynchronous Transfer Mode (ATM) and Multi-Protocol Label Switching (MPLS).</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="183-network-layer-performance"><strong>18.3 NETWORK-LAYER PERFORMANCE</strong></h3>
<p>The efficiency and reliability of the network layer are measured using the following metrics:</p><h4 id="1831-delay"><strong>18.3.1 Delay</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Types of Delay</strong>:<ol>
<li><strong>Propagation Delay</strong>: <ul>
<li>Time for a signal to travel from source to destination through the physical medium.</li>
<li>Formula: ( \text{Propagation Delay} = \frac{\text{Distance}}{\text{Propagation Speed}} )</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Transmission Delay</strong>: <ul>
<li>Time required to push all bits of a packet onto the transmission medium.</li>
<li>Formula: ( \text{Transmission Delay} = \frac{\text{Packet Size}}{\text{Bandwidth}} )</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Queuing Delay</strong>:<ul>
<li>Time a packet spends waiting in a router’s queue before being processed or transmitted.</li>
<li>Varies depending on network congestion.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Processing Delay</strong>:<ul>
<li>Time taken by a router to examine and forward a packet.</li>
<li>Includes route lookup, header parsing, and error checking.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="1832-throughput"><strong>18.3.2 Throughput</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Definition</strong>: The rate at which data is successfully transmitted and received over the network.</li>
<li><strong>Factors Affecting Throughput</strong>:<ul>
<li><strong>Bandwidth</strong>: The maximum data transfer rate of the medium.</li>
<li><strong>Network Congestion</strong>: Overloaded links or routers reduce throughput.</li>
<li><strong>Protocol Overhead</strong>: Header and control data can consume significant portions of bandwidth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="1833-packet-loss"><strong>18.3.3 Packet Loss</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Definition</strong>: The percentage of packets that fail to reach their destination due to errors, congestion, or buffer overflow at routers.</li>
<li><strong>Effects</strong>:<ul>
<li>Degrades the quality of real-time applications like VoIP or video streaming.</li>
<li>Increases retransmissions, causing further delays and congestion.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Mitigation Techniques</strong>:<ul>
<li>Implementing retransmission protocols (e.g., TCP).</li>
<li>Using redundant packet encoding to recover lost data.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="1834-congestion-control"><strong>18.3.4 Congestion Control</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Definition</strong>: Strategies to prevent and manage excessive packet buildup in the network.</li>
<li><strong>Techniques</strong>:<ol>
<li><strong>Traffic Shaping</strong>:<ul>
<li>Regulates the flow of data entering the network to prevent sudden bursts of traffic.</li>
<li>Example: Token Bucket and Leaky Bucket algorithms.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Packet Scheduling</strong>:<ul>
<li>Prioritizes certain packets based on their importance or type.</li>
<li>Example: First-Come-First-Serve (FCFS) and Priority Scheduling.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Retransmission Strategies</strong>:<ul>
<li>Automatically resends lost or corrupted packets.</li>
<li>Includes mechanisms like Automatic Repeat Request (ARQ).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="184-ipv4-addresses"><strong>18.4 IPv4 ADDRESSES</strong></h3>
<p>IPv4 addresses are a fundamental aspect of the network layer, ensuring that devices can be uniquely identified for communication.</p><h4 id="1841-address-space"><strong>18.4.1 Address Space</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>32-Bit Addressing</strong>: IPv4 uses a 32-bit structure, allowing for (2^{32}) unique addresses, approximately 4.3 billion.</li>
<li><strong>Depletion</strong>: Due to the rapid growth of devices, the IPv4 address space is nearly exhausted, leading to the adoption of solutions like NAT and IPv6.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="1842-classful-addressing"><strong>18.4.2 Classful Addressing</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li>IPv4 originally divided its address space into five classes, identified by the first few bits of the address:<ul>
<li><strong>Class A</strong>: <ul>
<li>Range: (0.0.0.0) to (127.255.255.255).</li>
<li>Large networks with up to (2^{24}) hosts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Class B</strong>:<ul>
<li>Range: (128.0.0.0) to (191.255.255.255).</li>
<li>Medium-sized networks with up to (2^{16}) hosts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Class C</strong>:<ul>
<li>Range: (192.0.0.0) to (223.255.255.255).</li>
<li>Small networks with up to (2^{8}) hosts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Class D</strong>:<ul>
<li>Range: (224.0.0.0) to (239.255.255.255).</li>
<li>Reserved for multicast communication.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Class E</strong>:<ul>
<li>Range: (240.0.0.0) to (255.255.255.255).</li>
<li>Reserved for experimental use.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="1843-classless-addressing"><strong>18.4.3 Classless Addressing</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>CIDR (Classless Inter-Domain Routing)</strong>:<ul>
<li>Eliminates rigid address classes, allowing for flexible allocation of IP addresses.</li>
<li>Uses <strong>prefix notation</strong> (e.g., (192.168.1.0/24)), where the “/24” indicates the number of bits in the network prefix.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Variable-Length Subnet Masking (VLSM)</strong>:<ul>
<li>Divides an IP address into subnets of different sizes.</li>
<li>Helps optimize address utilization and reduce wastage.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="1844-dynamic-host-configuration-protocol-dhcp"><strong>18.4.4 Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol (DHCP)</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Purpose</strong>:<ul>
<li>Automates the assignment of IP addresses, subnet masks, gateways, and DNS settings.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Advantages</strong>:<ul>
<li>Reduces manual configuration errors.</li>
<li>Allows for reusing IP addresses when devices leave the network.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Process</strong>:<ul>
<li>A device sends a <strong>DHCP Discovery</strong> request.</li>
<li>The server responds with a <strong>DHCP Offer</strong> containing configuration details.</li>
<li>The device accepts via a <strong>DHCP Request</strong>, and the server confirms with a <strong>DHCP Acknowledgment</strong>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="1845-network-address-translation-nat"><strong>18.4.5 Network Address Translation (NAT)</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Purpose</strong>:<ul>
<li>Allows multiple devices on a private network to share a single public IP address.</li>
<li>Conserves the limited IPv4 address space.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Types</strong>:<ul>
<li><strong>Static NAT</strong>: Maps one private IP to one public IP.</li>
<li><strong>Dynamic NAT</strong>: Maps private IPs to available public IPs from a pool.</li>
<li><strong>Port Address Translation (PAT)</strong>: Maps multiple private IPs to a single public IP using unique port numbers.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Advantages</strong>:<ul>
<li>Enhances security by hiding internal network structure.</li>
<li>Reduces the demand for public IP addresses.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="185-forwarding-of-ip-packets"><strong>18.5 FORWARDING OF IP PACKETS</strong></h3>
<p>Forwarding is the mechanism by which routers move packets from their source to the correct destination.</p><h4 id="1851-forwarding-based-on-destination-address"><strong>18.5.1 Forwarding Based on Destination Address</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Process</strong>:<ol>
<li>The router examines the destination IP address in the packet header.</li>
<li>It consults its <strong>routing table</strong> to determine the next hop.</li>
<li>The packet is forwarded to the next router or the final destination.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>Routing Table Entries</strong>:<ul>
<li><strong>Destination Network</strong>: Identifies the target subnet.</li>
<li><strong>Next Hop</strong>: The IP address of the next router.</li>
<li><strong>Metric</strong>: A value representing the cost or distance to the destination.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="1852-forwarding-based-on-label"><strong>18.5.2 Forwarding Based on Label</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Label-Based Forwarding</strong>:<ul>
<li>Utilized in <strong>Multiprotocol Label Switching (MPLS)</strong>.</li>
<li>Packets are assigned a <strong>label</strong> at the ingress router.</li>
<li>Intermediate routers use labels, not IP addresses, for forwarding decisions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Advantages</strong>:<ul>
<li>Faster forwarding as label lookups are simpler than IP-based routing.</li>
<li>Supports traffic engineering, allowing for efficient use of network resources.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="1853-routers-as-packet-switches"><strong>18.5.3 Routers as Packet Switches</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Functionality</strong>:<ul>
<li>Routers act as intelligent devices in packet-switched networks.</li>
<li>They handle:<ol>
<li>Receiving packets from the input interface.</li>
<li>Analyzing headers to determine the next hop.</li>
<li>Forwarding packets via the appropriate output interface.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Key Roles</strong>:<ul>
<li><strong>Packet Inspection</strong>: Examines headers for routing and QoS decisions.</li>
<li><strong>Routing Table Maintenance</strong>: Updates routes dynamically using protocols like OSPF or BGP.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="summary-of-key-concepts"><strong>Summary of Key Concepts</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Packet Switching</strong>: Core mechanism for efficient data transfer.</li>
<li><strong>Routing and Forwarding</strong>: Ensure packets traverse networks to reach their destination.</li>
<li><strong>IP Addressing</strong>: Vital for device identification and communication, with techniques like CIDR, DHCP, and NAT enhancing efficiency.</li>
<li><strong>Performance Metrics</strong>: Delay, throughput, and congestion control are essential for optimizing communication.</li>
<li><strong>DHCP and NAT</strong>: Critical protocols for managing IP address allocation and conservation.</li>
</ul>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Introduction to Network Layer</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ehmad</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.ehmad.site/introduction-to-network-layer/"/>
        <id>https://blog.ehmad.site/introduction-to-network-layer/</id>

        <updated>2025-01-08T08:53:46+05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Chapter 18: Introduction to Network Layer Network Layer Services Packetizing Process of breaking data into smaller packets for transmission Essential for efficient data transfer across networks Includes adding necessary headers with control information Routing and Forwarding Routing: Determining the best path for packets to reach&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h1 id="chapter-18-introduction-to-network-layer">Chapter 18: Introduction to Network Layer</h1>
<h2 id="network-layer-services">Network Layer Services</h2>
<h3 id="packetizing">Packetizing</h3>
<ul>
<li>Process of breaking data into smaller packets for transmission</li>
<li>Essential for efficient data transfer across networks</li>
<li>Includes adding necessary headers with control information</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="routing-and-forwarding">Routing and Forwarding</h3>
<ul>
<li>Routing: Determining the best path for packets to reach their destination</li>
<li>Forwarding: Moving packets from input ports to output ports in network devices</li>
<li>Both processes work together to ensure efficient packet delivery</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="other-services">Other Services</h3>
<ul>
<li>Quality of Service (QoS) management</li>
<li>Error control</li>
<li>Flow control</li>
<li>Congestion control</li>
<li>Packet sequencing</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="packet-switching">Packet Switching</h2>
<h3 id="datagram-approach-connectionless-service">Datagram Approach (Connectionless Service)</h3>
<ul>
<li>Each packet treated independently</li>
<li>No predetermined path</li>
<li>Packets may take different routes</li>
<li>More flexible but less reliable</li>
<li>Similar to postal service model</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="virtual-circuit-approach-connection-oriented-service">Virtual-Circuit Approach (Connection-Oriented Service)</h3>
<ul>
<li>Establishes dedicated path before data transfer</li>
<li>Three phases:<ol>
<li>Setup phase: Establishes the virtual circuit</li>
<li>Data transfer phase: Sends data along established path</li>
<li>Teardown phase: Terminates the connection</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>More reliable but less flexible</li>
<li>Similar to telephone system model</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="network-layer-performance">Network Layer Performance</h2>
<h3 id="delay">Delay</h3>
<ul>
<li>Types of delay:<ul>
<li>Processing delay: Time to examine packet header</li>
<li>Queuing delay: Waiting time in router buffers</li>
<li>Transmission delay: Time to push packet onto link</li>
<li>Propagation delay: Time for signal to travel through medium</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Total delay is sum of all delay types</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="throughput">Throughput</h3>
<ul>
<li>Rate of successful message delivery</li>
<li>Measured in bits per second (bps)</li>
<li>Affected by:<ul>
<li>Available bandwidth</li>
<li>Network congestion</li>
<li>Network hardware capabilities</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="packet-loss">Packet Loss</h3>
<ul>
<li>Occurs when network devices can’t process incoming packets</li>
<li>Common causes:<ul>
<li>Buffer overflow</li>
<li>Network congestion</li>
<li>Corrupted packets</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Requires retransmission mechanisms</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="congestion-control">Congestion Control</h3>
<ul>
<li>Methods to prevent/handle network congestion</li>
<li>Includes:<ul>
<li>Traffic shaping</li>
<li>Admission control</li>
<li>Resource reservation</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="ipv4-addresses">IPv4 Addresses</h2>
<h3 id="address-space">Address Space</h3>
<ul>
<li>32-bit addressing scheme</li>
<li>Supports approximately 4.3 billion unique addresses</li>
<li>Written in dotted-decimal notation</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="classful-addressing">Classful Addressing</h3>
<ul>
<li>Five classes: A, B, C, D, and E</li>
<li>Class A: Large networks (first bit 0)</li>
<li>Class B: Medium networks (first bits 10)</li>
<li>Class C: Small networks (first bits 110)</li>
<li>Class D: Multicast (first bits 1110)</li>
<li>Class E: Reserved (first bits 1111)</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="classless-addressing">Classless Addressing</h3>
<ul>
<li>CIDR (Classless Inter-Domain Routing)</li>
<li>More flexible than classful addressing</li>
<li>Uses variable-length subnet masks</li>
<li>Notation includes prefix length (e.g., /24)</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="dhcp-dynamic-host-configuration-protocol">DHCP (Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol)</h3>
<ul>
<li>Automatic IP address assignment</li>
<li>Four-step process:<ol>
<li>Discovery</li>
<li>Offer</li>
<li>Request</li>
<li>Acknowledgment</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Also provides additional network configuration information</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="nat-network-address-translation">NAT (Network Address Translation)</h3>
<ul>
<li>Allows private network addresses</li>
<li>Translates between private and public addresses</li>
<li>Helps conserve IPv4 addresses</li>
<li>Provides additional security</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="forwarding-of-ip-packets">Forwarding of IP Packets</h2>
<h3 id="forwarding-based-on-destination-address">Forwarding Based on Destination Address</h3>
<ul>
<li>Uses routing tables</li>
<li>Longest prefix matching</li>
<li>Next-hop determination</li>
<li>Route aggregation concepts</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="forwarding-based-on-label">Forwarding Based on Label</h3>
<ul>
<li>MPLS (Multi-Protocol Label Switching)</li>
<li>Uses labels instead of IP addresses</li>
<li>Faster processing</li>
<li>Better traffic engineering capabilities</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="routers-as-packet-switches">Routers as Packet Switches</h3>
<ul>
<li>Internal architecture</li>
<li>Switching fabric</li>
<li>Input/output port processing</li>
<li>Buffering mechanisms</li>
</ul>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Remove apps using ADB (Android Debug Bridge)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ehmad</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.ehmad.site/remove-apps-using-adb-android-debug-bridge/"/>
        <id>https://blog.ehmad.site/remove-apps-using-adb-android-debug-bridge/</id>

        <updated>2025-01-05T11:01:00+05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    You can remove apps using ADB (Android Debug Bridge) by following these steps: Connect Your Device: Verify ADB Connection: adb devices If prompted on your device, grant USB debugging permission. The terminal should display your device’s serial number, confirming the connection. List Installed Apps: adb&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>You can remove apps using <strong>ADB (Android Debug Bridge)</strong> by following these steps:</p><h3 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites:</h3>
<ol>
<li><strong>Enable Developer Options</strong> on your Android device:<ul>
<li>Go to <strong>Settings &gt; About phone</strong>.</li>
<li>Tap <strong>Build number</strong> seven times to enable Developer Options.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Enable USB Debugging</strong>:<ul>
<li>In <strong>Settings &gt; Developer Options</strong>, toggle on <strong>USB Debugging</strong>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Install ADB on your computer</strong>:<ul>
<li>Download the <strong>ADB and Fastboot platform tools</strong> from the <a href="https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/platform-tools">official Android Developer website</a>.</li>
<li>Extract the ZIP file to a folder on your computer.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<h3 id="steps-to-remove-apps-using-adb">Steps to Remove Apps Using ADB:</h3>
<ol>
<li><p><strong>Connect Your Device</strong>:</p><ul>
<li>Plug your Android device into your computer using a USB cable.</li>
<li>Ensure your device is set to <strong>File Transfer (MTP)</strong> mode if prompted.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Verify ADB Connection</strong>:</p><ul>
<li>Open a terminal (or Command Prompt) on your computer.</li>
<li>Navigate to the folder where you extracted the ADB tools.</li>
<li>Run the following command:<pre><code class="language-bash">adb devices
</code></pre>
</li>
<li>If prompted on your device, grant <strong>USB debugging permission</strong>.</li>
<li>The terminal should display your device’s serial number, confirming the connection.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>List Installed Apps</strong>:</p><ul>
<li>Run the following command to see a list of installed packages:<pre><code class="language-bash">adb shell pm list packages
</code></pre>
</li>
<li>This will return a list of package names (e.g., <code>com.example.app</code>).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Uninstall the App</strong>:</p><ul>
<li>Use the following command to uninstall an app:<pre><code class="language-bash">adb shell pm uninstall --user 0 &lt;package_name&gt;
</code></pre>
</li>
<li>Replace <code>&lt;package_name&gt;</code> with the package name of the app you want to remove.</li>
<li>Example:<pre><code class="language-bash">adb shell pm uninstall --user 0 com.facebook.katana
</code></pre>
</li>
<li>This removes the app for the current user but does not delete it from the system partition (useful for pre-installed apps).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Verify Uninstallation</strong>:</p><ul>
<li>Re-run the package list command to ensure the app is no longer listed:<pre><code class="language-bash">adb shell pm list packages
</code></pre>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<h3 id="notes">Notes:</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Pre-installed Apps</strong>: Using <code>--user 0</code> disables the app for the current user, which is usually sufficient. However, to permanently delete system apps, you would need root access.</li>
<li><strong>Reinstall Disabled Apps</strong>: To restore an uninstalled app:<pre><code class="language-bash">adb shell cmd package install-existing &lt;package_name&gt;
</code></pre>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Let me know if you need help with any specific app removal!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Windows package managers (CLI)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ehmad</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.ehmad.site/windows-package-managers-cli/"/>
        <id>https://blog.ehmad.site/windows-package-managers-cli/</id>

        <updated>2024-12-26T08:24:56+05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Windows offers several package managers that can simplify the process of installing and managing software. Here are some of the most popular ones: winget install &lt;package-name&gt; Example:winget install firefox List available packages:winget search &lt;package-name&gt; 2. Chocolatey Description: Chocolatey is one of the most popular package&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Windows offers several package managers that can simplify the process of installing and managing software. Here are some of the most popular ones:</p><h3 id="1-winget-windows-package-manager">1. <strong>winget (Windows Package Manager)</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Description</strong>: <code>winget</code> is a native Windows package manager developed by Microsoft. It allows you to search, install, update, and manage software from the command line.</li>
<li><strong>How to use</strong>:<ul>
<li><strong>Install</strong>: <code>winget</code> comes pre-installed on Windows 10 (starting with version 1809) and Windows 11.</li>
<li><strong>Install a package</strong>:<pre><code class="language-bash">winget install &lt;package-name&gt;
</code></pre>
</li>
<li><strong>Example</strong>:<pre><code class="language-bash">winget install firefox
</code></pre>
</li>
<li><strong>List available packages</strong>:<pre><code class="language-bash">winget search &lt;package-name&gt;
</code></pre>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="2-chocolatey">2. <strong>Chocolatey</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Description</strong>: Chocolatey is one of the most popular package managers for Windows. It works similarly to <code>apt</code> (on Linux) or <code>brew</code> (on macOS) and allows you to install software, update it, and manage dependencies easily.</li>
<li><strong>How to use</strong>:<ul>
<li><strong>Install</strong>:<ul>
<li>Open PowerShell as Administrator and run:<pre><code class="language-powershell">Set-ExecutionPolicy Bypass -Scope Process -Force; [System.Net.ServicePointManager]::SecurityProtocol = [System.Net.SecurityProtocolType]::Tls12; iex ((New-Object System.Net.WebClient).DownloadString(&#39;https://chocolatey.org/install.ps1&#39;))
</code></pre>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Install a package</strong>:<pre><code class="language-bash">choco install &lt;package-name&gt;
</code></pre>
</li>
<li><strong>Example</strong>:<pre><code class="language-bash">choco install googlechrome
</code></pre>
</li>
<li><strong>Update a package</strong>:<pre><code class="language-bash">choco upgrade &lt;package-name&gt;
</code></pre>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="3-scoop">3. <strong>Scoop</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Description</strong>: Scoop is a simple and powerful command-line installer for Windows. It focuses on simplicity and is popular among developers for installing development tools.</li>
<li><strong>How to use</strong>:<ul>
<li><strong>Install</strong>:
Open PowerShell and run:<pre><code class="language-powershell">Set-ExecutionPolicy RemoteSigned -Scope CurrentUser
iwr -useb get.scoop.sh | iex
</code></pre>
</li>
<li><strong>Install a package</strong>:<pre><code class="language-bash">scoop install &lt;package-name&gt;
</code></pre>
</li>
<li><strong>Example</strong>:<pre><code class="language-bash">scoop install git
</code></pre>
</li>
<li><strong>List available buckets</strong>:<pre><code class="language-bash">scoop bucket add &lt;bucket-name&gt;
</code></pre>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="4-ninite">4. <strong>Ninite</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Description</strong>: Ninite is a simple and easy-to-use tool that allows you to batch install popular software. It’s not exactly a package manager, but it automates the process of downloading and installing apps.</li>
<li><strong>How to use</strong>:<ul>
<li><strong>Download</strong> the Ninite installer from the Ninite website.</li>
<li><strong>Select the apps</strong> you want to install from the list on the Ninite website and download the custom installer.</li>
<li><strong>Run the installer</strong> to automatically install all selected software.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="5-appget">5. <strong>AppGet</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Description</strong>: AppGet is another package manager for Windows that provides a streamlined way to install software. It aims to be a more modern and stable package manager but is less widely used than the others.</li>
<li><strong>How to use</strong>:<ul>
<li><strong>Install</strong>: First, you need to install AppGet from its GitHub page or from the <a href="https://appget.net">AppGet website</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Install a package</strong>:<pre><code class="language-bash">appget install &lt;package-name&gt;
</code></pre>
</li>
<li><strong>Example</strong>:<pre><code class="language-bash">appget install vscode
</code></pre>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="6-portableapps">6. <strong>PortableApps</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Description</strong>: PortableApps isn’t a package manager in the traditional sense, but it provides a platform for running portable versions of popular software. It’s ideal if you prefer not to install software directly onto your system.</li>
<li><strong>How to use</strong>:<ul>
<li><strong>Download</strong> and install the <a href="https://portableapps.com/">PortableApps platform</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Install apps</strong> from the platform’s app store or manually by downloading portable versions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="7-msi-package-via-powershell">7. <strong>MSI Package (via PowerShell)</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Description</strong>: You can install MSI (Microsoft Installer) packages using PowerShell. This is more manual compared to the other package managers but gives you control over specific installations.</li>
<li><strong>How to use</strong>:<ul>
<li><strong>Install an MSI package</strong>:<pre><code class="language-powershell">msiexec /i &quot;C:\path\to\installer.msi&quot;
</code></pre>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="8-fdm-free-download-manager">8. <strong>FDM (Free Download Manager)</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Description</strong>: Free Download Manager isn’t exactly a package manager, but it supports downloading installers and automating installation tasks.</li>
<li><strong>How to use</strong>:<ul>
<li>Use it to download software or package files, and it will assist in managing the downloads.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="comparison-overview">Comparison Overview:</h3>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Package Manager</th>
<th>Ease of Use</th>
<th>Package Availability</th>
<th>Best For</th>
<th>Official Site</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody><tr>
<td><strong>winget</strong></td>
<td>Easy</td>
<td>Good</td>
<td>General use, Windows apps</td>
<td><a href="https://github.com/microsoft/winget-cli">https://github.com/microsoft/winget-cli</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Chocolatey</strong></td>
<td>Easy</td>
<td>Excellent</td>
<td>General use, productivity software</td>
<td><a href="https://chocolatey.org">https://chocolatey.org</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Scoop</strong></td>
<td>Easy</td>
<td>Good</td>
<td>Developer tools</td>
<td><a href="https://scoop.sh">https://scoop.sh</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Ninite</strong></td>
<td>Very Easy</td>
<td>Limited</td>
<td>Quick batch installation</td>
<td><a href="https://ninite.com">https://ninite.com</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>AppGet</strong></td>
<td>Easy</td>
<td>Moderate</td>
<td>Software management</td>
<td><a href="https://appget.net">https://appget.net</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>PortableApps</strong></td>
<td>Very Easy</td>
<td>Limited</td>
<td>Portable apps</td>
<td><a href="https://portableapps.com">https://portableapps.com</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>MSI via PowerShell</strong></td>
<td>Manual</td>
<td>Depends on the MSI file</td>
<td>Specific app installs</td>
<td>N/A</td>
</tr>
</tbody></table>
<p>Each of these package managers has its strengths and use cases. <strong>winget</strong>, <strong>Chocolatey</strong>, and <strong>Scoop</strong> are widely used for general-purpose package management, while <strong>Ninite</strong> is useful for batch installation, and <strong>PortableApps</strong> is great for portable software.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to Fix WebDAV Connection Issues in Windows and Map a WebDAV Drive</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ehmad</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.ehmad.site/how-to-fix-webdav-connection-issues-in-windows-and-map-a-webdav-drive/"/>
        <id>https://blog.ehmad.site/how-to-fix-webdav-connection-issues-in-windows-and-map-a-webdav-drive/</id>

        <updated>2024-12-14T15:14:46+05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    WebDAV (Web-based Distributed Authoring and Versioning) is a protocol that allows users to manage and share files over the web. While connecting to a WebDAV endpoint is straightforward on many platforms, Windows users may encounter challenges, such as errors while mapping WebDAV drives or accessing&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>WebDAV (Web-based Distributed Authoring and Versioning) is a protocol that allows users to manage and share files over the web. While connecting to a WebDAV endpoint is straightforward on many platforms, Windows users may encounter challenges, such as errors while mapping WebDAV drives or accessing files. This guide explains how to troubleshoot common WebDAV issues and successfully map a WebDAV drive in Windows.</p><hr>
<h2 id="common-webdav-issues-in-windows"><strong>Common WebDAV Issues in Windows</strong></h2>
<p>Some common errors while attempting to map a WebDAV drive in Windows include:</p><ol>
<li><strong>“System error 67 has occurred”</strong>: Indicates that Windows could not find the specified network resource.</li>
<li><strong>“The network name cannot be found”</strong>: Often caused by URL formatting issues or an inactive WebClient service.</li>
<li><strong>Login prompts with valid credentials</strong>: Indicates a mismatch between authentication requirements or unsupported protocols.</li>
<li><strong>“The folder you entered does not appear to be valid”</strong>: Usually occurs when Windows cannot verify the WebDAV endpoint.</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<h2 id="steps-to-map-a-webdav-drive-in-windows"><strong>Steps to Map a WebDAV Drive in Windows</strong></h2>
<h3 id="1-test-the-webdav-url"><strong>1. Test the WebDAV URL</strong></h3>
<p>Before mapping a drive, ensure the WebDAV server is working correctly:</p><ol>
<li>Open a web browser and visit your WebDAV URL (e.g., <code>https://example.com/webdav</code>).</li>
<li>Verify that you can log in and access the files.</li>
</ol>
<p>If the URL works in the browser, proceed to the next step. If not, check your server settings or consult your server administrator.</p><hr>
<h3 id="2-use-the-correct-unc-path-for-webdav"><strong>2. Use the Correct UNC Path for WebDAV</strong></h3>
<p>Windows requires a specific UNC format for WebDAV connections over HTTPS. Use the following syntax:</p><pre><code>\\hostname@SSL\path
</code></pre>
<p>For example:</p><ul>
<li>If your WebDAV URL is <code>https://example.com/webdav</code>, the UNC path would be:<pre><code>\\example.com@SSL\webdav
</code></pre>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="3-map-the-webdav-drive"><strong>3. Map the WebDAV Drive</strong></h3>
<p>To map a WebDAV drive in Windows:</p><ol>
<li>Open <strong>Command Prompt</strong> as Administrator.</li>
<li>Run the following command:<pre><code class="language-cmd">net use Y: \\example.com@SSL\webdav /user:YourUsername YourPassword /persistent:yes
</code></pre>
<ul>
<li>Replace <code>Y:</code> with your desired drive letter.</li>
<li>Replace <code>YourUsername</code> and <code>YourPassword</code> with your WebDAV credentials.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<p>If successful, you’ll see a confirmation message. The drive will now appear in File Explorer.</p><hr>
<h3 id="4-enable-the-webclient-service"><strong>4. Enable the WebClient Service</strong></h3>
<p>The Windows WebDAV client relies on the WebClient service. Ensure it’s running:</p><ol>
<li>Press <code>Win + R</code>, type <code>services.msc</code>, and press Enter.</li>
<li>Locate <strong>WebClient</strong> in the list.</li>
<li>If the service is stopped, right-click and select <strong>Start</strong>.</li>
<li>Set the <strong>Startup Type</strong> to <strong>Automatic</strong>.</li>
</ol>
<p>Restart the service if necessary.</p><hr>
<h3 id="5-configure-windows-for-basic-authentication"><strong>5. Configure Windows for Basic Authentication</strong></h3>
<p>Some WebDAV servers use Basic Authentication, which may need to be explicitly enabled in Windows:</p><ol>
<li>Press <code>Win + R</code>, type <code>regedit</code>, and press Enter.</li>
<li>Navigate to:<pre><code>HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SYSTEM\CurrentControlSet\Services\WebClient\Parameters
</code></pre>
</li>
<li>Modify or create the following registry keys:<ul>
<li><strong>BasicAuthLevel</strong>: Set this DWORD value to <code>2</code> (enables Basic Authentication over HTTPS).</li>
<li><strong>UseBasicAuth</strong>: Set this DWORD value to <code>1</code>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Restart the WebClient service after making these changes.</p><hr>
<h3 id="6-save-webdav-credentials"><strong>6. Save WebDAV Credentials</strong></h3>
<p>To avoid repeated login prompts, save your WebDAV credentials:</p><ol>
<li>Open <strong>Control Panel</strong> &gt; <strong>Credential Manager</strong>.</li>
<li>Add a new <strong>Windows Credential</strong>:<ul>
<li>Network address: <code>example.com</code></li>
<li>Username: Your WebDAV username.</li>
<li>Password: Your WebDAV password.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<h3 id="7-address-webdav-upload-limits"><strong>7. Address WebDAV Upload Limits</strong></h3>
<p>If your WebDAV server limits file uploads (e.g., 100 MB):</p><ol>
<li>Adjust the upload size limit on the server. For example:<ul>
<li><strong>Apache</strong>: Increase <code>LimitRequestBody</code> and <code>php.ini</code> file size limits.</li>
<li><strong>Nginx</strong>: Increase <code>client_max_body_size</code>.</li>
<li><strong>IIS</strong>: Modify the <code>maxAllowedContentLength</code> property.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Use chunked uploads if supported by your WebDAV client.</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<h3 id="8-test-with-third-party-webdav-clients"><strong>8. Test with Third-Party WebDAV Clients</strong></h3>
<p>If Windows fails to connect, try a third-party WebDAV client:</p><ul>
<li><strong>Cyberduck</strong>: An open-source client for managing WebDAV connections.</li>
<li><strong>WinSCP</strong>: A robust tool for FTP, SFTP, and WebDAV.</li>
<li><strong>RaiDrive</strong>: Maps WebDAV as a network drive with additional configuration options.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="troubleshooting-common-errors"><strong>Troubleshooting Common Errors</strong></h2>
<h3 id="error-system-error-67-has-occurred"><strong>Error: System Error 67 Has Occurred</strong></h3>
<p>This error typically occurs due to:</p><ul>
<li>Incorrect URL formatting: Use <code>\\hostname@SSL\path</code>.</li>
<li>The WebClient service not running: Start the service via <code>services.msc</code>.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="error-login-prompt-fails-despite-correct-credentials"><strong>Error: Login Prompt Fails Despite Correct Credentials</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Check server-side authentication settings.</li>
<li>Save credentials in the Credential Manager.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="error-the-folder-you-entered-does-not-appear-to-be-valid"><strong>Error: The Folder You Entered Does Not Appear to Be Valid</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Use the UNC format (<code>\\hostname@SSL\path</code>).</li>
<li>Ensure the WebClient service is running.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="conclusion"><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>
<p>Mapping a WebDAV drive in Windows requires careful attention to URL formatting, service configuration, and authentication settings. By following the steps outlined in this guide, you can successfully resolve connection issues and map your WebDAV drive. If problems persist, third-party WebDAV clients can provide additional flexibility and troubleshooting insights.</p><p>Let me know if you’d like to customize this article further!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
